SAIMA SHARLEEN ISLAM

J +880-1827537100 \boxtimes saimasharleen10@gmail.com \boxtimes saimasharleen

aimasharleen aimasharleen

Objectives

A diligent, amiable, and articulate individual who is passionate about building up a flourishing research career across AI, Machine Learning and it's applications, Data Science, Computer Vision. I have mainly worked with machine learning algorithms and it applications in the field of data science. I bring with me, my strong passion for technology and quick learning capability.

Education

American International University-Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Software Engineering (CGPA: 3.42 /4.00)

May 2016 – Feb 2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Work Experience

Cystem Arts Apr 2020 — Mar 2021

Software Engineer

- Assisted in development of the front end of a client's website.
- Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to do the modifications.

American International University-Bangladesh

Sep 2019 — Dec 2019

Teaching Assistant

- Dhaka, Bangladesh
- Assisted the students in project for Advanced Topics In Programming III course
- Performed regular data entry tasks on students' evaluation grades

Battery Low Interactive

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

Intern, Web Development and Content Writing

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to complete the assign tasks.
- Created different contents for the company.

Research Interests

Machine Learning, Deep Learning & its applications, Computer Vision, Data Science

Research Experience

Application of Machine Learning Algorithms to Predict the Thyroid Risk: An Experimental Comparative Study

• Compared various algorithms for increasing the accuracy of thyroid disease prediction using the UCI thyroid data collection. (Submitted to IEEE Access)

Predictable Crime and Disease Occurrence Rate by Analyzing Different News Sources

• If any crime occurred any particular area then a lot of newspaper publishes a report about that crime or television also report about that crime as well as radio. Every one of those reports can easily be found on the web. For any kind of disease is spreading out in any particular area then the media publish a report about that disease. From those sources, we are planning to build a crime or disease database. So, our main goal is developing an accurate, better and efficient pattern so that we can easily identify the crime and disease of any area. (Currently work on progress)

UG Thesis: Human Detection in Crowd using Video Surveillance System

• Using YOLO detected human in crowd in AIUB premises.

Publications

Conference Paper:

An Empirical Survey on Crowdsourcing-Based Data Management Techniques
 Accepted for the International Conference on Computing Advancements ICCA 2020

Standardized Tests

International English Language Test (IELTS):

Aggregate: 7, Listening: 8, Reading: 7, Speaking: 7, Writing: 6

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, c#

Database: SQL (MySQL,Oracle,Postgres), MongoDB

Tools: Git, VS Code, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Overleaf, TeXworks, PyCharm, Mendeley

Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, OpenCV Web Techologies: Laravel, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Nodejs

Academic Projects

Extra Food Distribution Management System | HTML, CSS, Java script, Bootstrap, PHP, My SQL

- Overview: A platform for the Restaurant owner, Volunteer, Admin, Event Manager and General User. The owner can post for leftover foods, and a volunteer will pick up the foods and later will donate food in a specific location.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Extra-Food-Distribution-Management-System-Web-Technologies-

Nirjhor | c++, openal

- Overview: Nirjhor is basically a scenery-based project using opengl.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Nirjhor-Graphics-Project-

Fashion $\mid bootstrap, css, javascript, html$

- Overview: Fashion is basically a web design project.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Fashion-Web-Design

Online Courses

- 1. IBM Data Science Professional Certificate: (On Going)
- 2. Data Science Math Skills-Duke University: (On Going)

Awards & Achievements

• Ada Lovelace Datathon 2021

Team Position: 8th Team Name: Panda-15

Standing Link: https://www.kaggle.com/c/alc-datathon-2021/leaderboard

National Girls' Programming Contest 2018

Team Name: AIUB Incognito

Standing Link: https://algo.codemarshal.org/contests/ngpc18/standings

The Duke of Edinburgh's International Award

The Bronze Standard

Hult Prize at AIUB

2nd Runner Up

World Literature Centre Book Reading Program

Winner

Extracurricular Activities

Firefox at AIUB June 2018 - Feb 2020

Club Lead

American International University-Bangladesh

- Managed executive board of 8 members and ran weekly meetings to oversee progress in essential parts of the chapter.
- Led chapter of 50+ members to work towards goals that improve and promote opensource and improve community service.

References

Md. Saef Ullah Miah

Assistant Professor(On-leave) Department of Computer Science American International University-Bangladesh ⊠ md.saefullah@gmail.com

Md. Al-Amin

Lecturer

Department of Computer Science American International University-Bangladesh alamin@aiub.edu

Dr. Dip Nandi

Professor and Director Faculty of Science and Technology American International University-Bangladesh ⊠ dip.nandi@aiub.edu